For Oscar, every day is an adventure
Chimpanzee is a documentary film directed by Alastair Fothergill.
A nature documentary centered on a family of chimps living
in the Ivory Coast and Ugandan rain forests.
Through Oscar, a little chimpanzee, we discover learning about life in the heart of the African
tropical forest and follow his first steps in this world with humor, emotion and anguish.
Following a tragedy, he finds himself separated from his mother
and left alone to face the hostility of the jungle.
Until he is picked up by an older chimpanzee, who
will take him under her protection.
Narrator (voice), played by Tim Allen.
Chimpanzee is a 2012 nature documentary film about a young common chimpanzee named Oscar who finds himself alone in the
African forests until he is adopted by another chimpanzee, who takes him in and treats him like his own child.
The American release of the film is narrated by Tim Allen.
The film was produced by Disneynature and directed by
Alastair Fothergill and Mark Linfield.
It is the sixth nature documentary released under the Disneynature label, following Earth, The
Crimson Wing: Mystery of the Flamingos, Oceans, Wings of Life, and African Cats.
It was released in theaters on April 20, 2012, just before Earth Day, April 22.
The film explores themes of chimp, wilderness, uganda, wildlife, wild animal.